Engr. Justin D. de Guia

justin.dayaodeguia@gmail.com | https://github.com/jddeguia | 09064364508 | Manila, Philippines

OVERVIEW



Licensed electronics engineer with over 2 years of experience in the field of research and academia looking for an opportunity in *data analytics* and *software development*. A graduate student researcher focusing his studies related to application of artificial intelligence in solar energy management such as *forecasting*, *classification*, and *anomaly detection*. Knowledgeable in programming languages such as *C*, *Python*, *Java*, and *MySQL* query. Bringing forth self-starter attitude and work-ethic. All of my works and personal projects can be found at https://github.com/jddeguia

RELEVANT WORK EXPERIENCE

Graduate Student Researcher

De La Salle University

May 2019- December 2020

- Doing research about solar energy management system under De La Salle University- Intelligent System Laboratory
- Publishes paper related to application of machine learning algorithms and neural networks to solar energy management system
- Gives detailed and professional commentary to the research papers submitted to IEEE HNICEM and TENCON

Faculty Adamson University June 2018-May 2019

Taught subjects for students specializing in science and engineering such as technical drawing, physics, and quantitative research

EDUCATION

De La Salle University

December 2018- December 2020 (Expected Graduation)

Master of Science in Electronics and Communications Engineering major in Artificial Intelligence

CGPA: 3.9000

University of the City of Manila (Pamantasan ng Lungsod ng Maynila)

Bachelor of Science in Electronics and Communications Engineering

June 2011- April 2016 CGPA: 2.2500

SKILLS

- Programming: C, Python, Java, MySQL Query
- Programming Principles: Object-oriented design and programming
- Data Analysis and Visualization: Numpy, pandas, matplotlib, seaborn, Tableau
- Machine Learning Algorithms and Neural Networks: tensorflow, scikitlearn
- Electronic Design: Arduino, Raspberry Pi, PCB design, microprocessor programming

PERSONAL RESEARCH AND PUBLISHED JOURNAL

- Performance Comparison of Classification Algorithms for Diagnosing Chronic Kidney Disease
 - https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/9073568
- Using Stacked Long Short-Term Memory with Principal Component Analysis for Short Term Prediction of Solar Irradiance based on Weather Patterns
 - o https://github.com/jddeguia/compare-forecast-models
- Solar Irradiance Prediction Based on Weather Patterns Using Bagging-Based Ensemble Learners with Principal Component Analysis

 https://github.com/jddeguia/bagging-lstm
- Application of Ensemble Learning with Mean Shift Clustering for Output Profile Classification and Anomaly Detection in Energy Production of Grid-Tied Photovoltaic System
 - https://github.com/jddeguia/anomaly-detection-bagging-mlp
 - https://github.com/jddeguia/energy-output-profiling

AWARDS AND CERTIFICATIONS

- Philippine government scholarship recipient (May 2019-December 2020): Recipient of Department of Science and Technology-Engineering Research and Development Technology (DOST-ERDT) for graduate student. Enjoys full scholarship with monthly stipend
- Licensure for Electronics and Communications Engineer (October 2017): license for electronics engineer awarded by Philippine Professional Regulation Commission (PRC)